"Solidarity" Information Office in Canada records CPAA 95.13
Connecticut Polish American Archives
"Solidarity" Information Office in Canada records
1980-1995
CPAA 95.13
Connecticut Polish American Archives
6.0 Linear feet
The Solidarity Information Office in Canada was opened in Toronto in 1981, and served as a satellite office of the Solidarity Coordinating Office Abroad in Brussels. Zygmunt Przetakiewicz was the director of the office from 1981 until 1983, and in 1983 Wojciech Gilewski was a director of the office until 1990, when it discontinued operation. The collection consists of extensive correspondence, reports, official publications, press releases and clippings. It covers the years from 1981 until 1990.
Gilewski, Wojciech
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes extensive correspondence, reports and memos from the coordinating office in Brussels, press releases, various Solidarity publications abroad, clippings, pamphlets, and information about contacts with other Solidarity groups and offices abroad. It covers the years that the Solidarity Office operated, from 1981 through 1990.
Biographical/Historical note
The Solidarity Information office in Canada, a non-profit organization, opened in Toronto in 1981, and served as a satellite office of the Solidarity Coordinating Office Abroad in Brussels. Zygmunt Przetakiewicz was the first director of the office from 1981 until 1983. In 1983 Wojcich Gilewski took over and remained director until 1990 when it discontinued operation. The office closely cooperated with Canadian trade unions and Polish Canadian organizations. Their primary duties were to disseminate information about NSZZ “Solidarnosc” throughout Canada and the Polish community. Although operated independently of other social and political organizations, one being the Canadian Labour Union, it was the goal to work amicably with other Polish Canadian groups, such as the Canadian Polish Congress.
Clippings.; Conference of Solidarity Support Organizations; Correspondence.; NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization) -- History; Poland -- History -- 1980-1989 -- Periodicals; Solidarity International
- Solidarity Information Office-Log of outgoing correspondence., 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Solidarity Information Office-outgoing correspondence, pt.1., 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Solidarity Information Office-outgoing correspondence, pt.2, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Solidarity Information Office-incoming correspondence, pt.1, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Solidarity Information Office-incoming correspondence, pt.2, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Solidarity Information Office-incoming correspondence, pt.3, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, press releases, testimony from prisoners–telex., 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Walesa’s visit in Canada and USA-Planning and correspondence., 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Zurich Declaration, Dec. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Coordinating Office Abroad NSZZ Solidarnosc, Brussels-declarations, statements, correspondence., 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Solidarnosc Information Office - London [M.Garztecki] - Correspondence, newsletters., 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Polish Solidarity Campaign, Reports., 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mailing lists: Solidarity support groups in Canada, media Contacts., 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Solidarity Information Office in Canada - application for Incorporation., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Solidarity Information Office in Canada- Press releases, event planning, correspondence., 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Solidarity Information Office in Canada - press releases, declarations, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Information for people interested in immigrating to Canada., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Texts from Poland disseminated by Solidarity Information Office in Canada., 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- August 31, 1983- Rally commemorating the creation of Solidarity. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- W. Gilewski - interviews, letters to the editor, application for employment, etc., 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- “Perspektywy udzialu nowej emigracji w zyciu organizacyjnym” [Gilewski?], 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Comite pur la Defense des Prisoners Politiques d’Europe de l’Est, Montreal., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- “Solidarnosc” with the Pope Committee, Canadian Group, Toronto., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Conseil D’Action Solidarnosc, Quebec., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- East European Solidarity Committee, Edmonton., 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Polish Workers Solidarity Committee, St. Catharines; Ontario Act of Disarmament Coalition 1982-1988; 2 full editions of the Activist 1987. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Solidarity Support Committee of Toronto- advertisements, correspondence., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Vancouver Committee for Solidarity with Solidarnosc- Events, correspondence, "The Activist" (1987)., 1981-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Polish Socio-Political Group ”Independence-Solidarity”, Calgary, Alberta., 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Ousting of Zygmunt Przetakiewicz by Canadian Labor Congress., 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Kontakt & other groups in France., 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Solidarity Information Office in Canada-By-laws., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Film proposal “Solidarity” by Przemek Byszewski., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Canadian Confederation of Solidarity Support Organization., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Relief Committee for Political Prisoners in Poland, Toronto., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Friends of Solidarnosc Association, South Burnaby, British Columbia., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Committee for Solidarity with Poland, Regina, Sask; Rally., 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Solidarity Assistance Association, Ottawa announcement., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Guelph, Ontario “Solidarity” Support Committee., 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Solidarnosc Emigracji-Emigracja Solidarnosci (The Solidarity of Emigration-The Emigration of Solidarity), Edmonton, Alberta., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Friends of Solidarity, Edmonton, Alberta- bulletins and correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Association of Friends of Solidarnosc, Vancouver., 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Friends of Solidarity, Kitchener-Waterloo., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Biuro Informacyjne KPN w (Confederation of Independent Poland Information Bureau), Calgary 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- East European Solidarity Committee, Edmonton, Alberta., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Stowarzyszenie Przyjaciol Solidarnosci, Calgary., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Solidarity Association, Antigonish, Nova Scotia 1982-85; “War Through the Eyes of Children” 1982., 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Polish Canadian Action Group, Toronto., 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Action Group in Support of Solidarnosc, Montreal, Quebec., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Conference of Solidarity Support Organizations., 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Committee in Support of Solidarity, New York., 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Joseph Losiak- POMOST, Chicago., 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Solidarnosc-Venezuela-correspondence., 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Support of Solidarity, Boston, Massachusetts., 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Friends of Solidarity, Georgetown University, Washington D.C., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Coordinating Information Office NSZZ Solidarnosc in Bremen, West Germany., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- NSZZ Solidarnosc, Information Bureau in Australia., 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Solidarity Clubs of Democratic and Independent Poland in Stockholm, Sweden., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Solidarity Support Committee of Rhode Island - Correspondence., 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- The Friends of Solidarity Families Project, Buffalo., 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Solidarity, California., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Poland Watch Center, Washington D.C., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Voice for Independent Poland, California., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- “Kwiaty dla mojego miasta” by Anna Kuc; “Sprawozdanie z dzialalnosci w NSZZ Solidarnosc” by Ryszard Kuc; personal data sheet., 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Former internees and political prisoners that settled in Canada. No date., 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Internment decisions., 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Committee of Former Internees in Canda., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Brotherhood of Dispersed Solidarity Members, Chicago., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Canadian Polish Congress- General information, correspondence., 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Polish Question at the Madrid Conference on Security and Co-operation in Europe (CSCE) - brief by Polish National Fund to Ambassador R.L. Rodgers., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Free World Polonia Coordinating Council, Komunikat no.4., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- “Poles in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, June 1989" Free World Polonia Coordinating Council, Toronto. (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Polish Society of Music in Toronto- programs., 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Canadian Labour Congress (CLC)-Press releases, newsletters, correspondence., 1981-1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Canadian Labour Congress- Position papers., 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Canadian Labor Congress (scattered issues), 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- The Canadian Tribute to Human Rights/Solidarnosc Tribute., 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Free Labour World (scattered issues)., 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- International Confederation of Federal Trade Unions- Trade Union Rights - survey of violations 1983/1984, 1984/1985, 1985/1986, 1986/1987, 1988., 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- International Confederation on Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)., 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- International Labour Office (ILO)., 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Statements by Ambassador William Bauer at 1986 CSCE meeting; Speech by Joe Clark, Sec. Of State at 1989 & 1990 CSCE., 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Canada’s human rights policy., 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Meeting of Experts on Human Rights, Ottawa., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Political prisoners in Poland - various documents., 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- News from Poland - AP, Reuter 1983 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Amnesty International - campaigns on behalf of Polish political prisoners, pt.1., 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Amnesty International - campaigns on behalf of Polish political prisoners, pt.2, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Helsinki Committee in Poland - various reports., 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Canadian Government and House of Commons- Various documents., 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Documents of the Second National Congress [of Solidarity], Gdansk 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Registration of NSZZ Solidarnosc., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Workers Unions by-laws., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Situation in Poland - various reports., 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Charitable gifts to Poland., 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Polish-Jewish relations., 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Meeting between J.Cyrankiewicz, R. Wojna and Australian and Canadian delegation in Vienna, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Human Rights, Ottawa 1985 - statement by Polish government (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Free Workers Unions by-laws in Ursus, Warsaw, Poland., 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Wiadomosc i Pokoj (Freedom and Peace) 1985 & 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- The Round Table Accords., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "Polonian Enterprises and Private Enterprise in Poland: The Reality of the So-Called Green Light”, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Aid for Poland., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Film about “Wujek Mine" tragedy., 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- International Fund for Polish Students., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Selected Polish writers., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Proposal for Funding of “Training for Democracy”, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Elections 1989 - fliers (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Solidarity Collection, University of Toronto - General alphabetical index., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Solidarity Collection at University of Toronto - finding aids: Guide to Slavic and East European Resources and Facilities of the University of Toronto Library, The Solidarity Collection, Pre-Solidarity Master File, Solidarity Legal Master File, Martial Law Period Master File, Post-Martial law Period., 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Position on social and economic reform of the country - Network of Solidarity organizations in Leading Factories, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- “NSZZ Solidarnosc - terazniejszosc i perspektywy”, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- “Economic program of Solidarity” by Rudolf Cujes n.d. 1982?, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- “Od sciany do sciany” by Helena Kowalik [about Ursus in 1980-1981] in: Ekspres reporterow, KAW, 1981 (Polish) (Box 3, Folder 28)
- “Evolution of Polish Underground” by Leonard Pluta., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- “Poland: Three years after”, A Report on Human Rights, December 1984. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- “Soviet Persecution of Religion in Ukraine”, Toronto, Canada 1976. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Zalewska M., “Solidarity Underground: Free Trade Unionism in Poland Today”, London, August, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- “The Church in Poland under Martial Law” NSZZ “Solidarnosc” Information Office, London, June 1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- “by nie pekla jak oplatek cienka sciana dzielaca nas od nienawisci”, Komitet Koordynacyjny NSZZ “Solidarnosc” we Francji., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Achmatowicz Aleksander, “Jak doszlo do zmiany w programie nauczania historii w szkole”, Warszawa., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- “The Underground Structure of Solidarity” by m. Kolodziej in: RAD Background Report/30, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Zwiazki “Solidarnosci” z Zachodem, in: “Solidarnosc: fronty walki o wladze” by J. Borowiecki., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- “Droga do wladzy: prawda o polskiej kontrrewolucji”, Wydzial Informacji KC PZPR., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- “Zakazane piosenki-troche smutno” [comp. By J.S.], Edmonton., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- “Solidarnosc: the hope from Gdansk” film by Henrik Byrn., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- “Progress of knowledge and the right - left dichotomy: are the existing ideologies adequate?” by Jerzy A. Wojciechowski., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- “On Gogol Boulevard: networking bulletin for activists East and West", (NY) Vol. 1 No. 3/4 (1988), Vol. 1 No. 2(1987-88), Vol. 2 No. 1/2(1988)., 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Volya: International Bulletin on Eastern Europe and the USSR no.15, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- International Kontactos, vol. 1-2 (1988) (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Publications of Solidarity Support Groups list, 1982 Solidarity International New York. (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Nobel Prize for Peace (Premis Nobel de la Paz), published by ICFTU., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- “State Against the Nation, Poland, 1981-85" by Leonard Pluta., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- “Poland and the war of information” by H. Fedorowicz “Civil society as a communication project” by H. Fedorowicz., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- “Niepodleglosc” no.23-25 - reprint by Reduta, Islington, Ontario., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- "Overview on the Polish People’s Republic", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- "The Implications of Poland’s Entry into the International Monetary Fund", 1985 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Democratic League of Independent Trade Unions (FSZDL) News no.1, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- List z Kurkowej by Adam Michnik n.d., 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Uwagi o dzialalnosci TKN by A. Jawlowska n.d., 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Accord Rzeszow -Ustrzyki Dolne (farmers), 1981 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Vietnamese Association, Toronto., 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- “The Vision for Humanity: the Pope in Canada” Canadian Labour Congress, October, 1984. (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Miscellaneous essays, correspondence, etc, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Publications separated from 95-13 (see Polish Heritage Collection and Polish Underground Collection)., 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Miscellaneous correspondence., 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Cooperation agreement between regional committees of Solidarity and Western trade unions., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Texts by Lech A. Biegalski n.d., 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Ruch Polski Suwerennej “17 wrzesnia”, London, Ontario, Canada, n.d., 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- “Wole Lecha” Kampania prezydencka w Polsce., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Tygodnik Solidarnosc, Komisja Krajowa NSZZ Solidarnosc,Warszawa (scattered issues 1981) (Box 4, Object 1)
- Various periodicals- “Les Droits” [Text form Helsinki Committee in Poland, autorized by Z. Bujak, W. Hardek, B.Lis, J.Pinior,E.Szumiejko, Poland 1983];“Til Lech Walesa Og Ideer “Solidarnosc” by Barbara Ur, Andrzej Jan Piwarski, Krzesislaw Piwarski; “Solidarity” by Jain Ajit, USA 1983; 1984 "Des droits de l’homme et du citoyen en Republique Populaire de Pologne, Rapport par Le Comite Helsinki en Pologne", Belgium, 1985; "Studia i Materialy", Jan.-March, Osrodek Prac Spol. Zaw. NSZZ Solidarnosc, Warszawa 1990; Dokumenty, no.3/4- 31/12/82 - 30/01/83, Biuro Solidarnosci, Sweden; KOSMAS, Journal of Czechoslovak and Central European Studies, vol. 3 and 4, Winter 1984/Summer 1985;“Rapport” La Polodne cinq ans apres aout, NSZZ Solidarnosc, Belgium 1986; The Polish Trade Union in 1984, by Bogdan Lis for the Temporary Coordinating Commission (TKK), Poland 1984; NSZZ “Solidarnosc” on reforming the Polish economy, Belgium 1987; NSZZ “Solidarnosc” on Poland in 1985, Belgium 1986; Participation Solidarite, Section Polonaise De La C.S.C. Bureau D’Information “Solidarnosc”, Belgium, 1983; Czardara, zapamietaj, Bureau International Afghanistan[1985]; Polska bez cenzury, independent imprints from Poland [1984-1990?]; Le Programme de Solidarnosc, Gda_sk, Oct.7 1981, Presses Universitaires De Lille, 1982; Utrzymac i wzmocnic, Confederation Generale Du Travail, Paris, [1982-1989?]; Les Sept de Solidarnosc, Comite de Coordination du Syndicat “Solidarnosc” in France; Repressions in Poland: State of War, Coordinating Office Abroad of NSZZ “Solidarnosc”, Belgium; Report of IMF Mission to Poland, December 1980, International Metalworkers’ Federation, Switzerland; Koriakov, Mikhail, 1911, “ Pokaianie Khrushcheva: po stranitsam vospominanii byvshego Pervogo sekretaria TSK KPSS i predsedatelia Soveta ministrov SSSR; Prokop, Myroslaw, “ Ukraïna i ukraïnska polityka Moskvy”, Sucasnist, 1981; “Solidarnost o rabochem dvizhenii v Polshe i o rabochem dvizhenii v Rossii”, Frankfurt a. Main: Posev, c1982; Pruss, Witold, “Rewolucja 1905 roku w Krolestwie Polskim”, Warszawa: Instytut Wydawniczy Zwiazkow Zawodowych, 198; Wojcik, Zbigniew, 1922-, “ Rola Jozefa Pilsudskiego w odzyskaniu niepodleglosci Polski”, Warszawa: Instytut Wydawniczy Zwiazkow Zawodowych, 1981; Ksiazka pamiatkowa Polonii, Okregu Kitchener, Ontario Kanada: zbior materialow historyczno kronikarskich obejmujacych dzialalnosc organizacji polskich na terenie Kitchener, Guelph, Galt, Preston: 966 1857 1966 / w opracowaniu redakcyjnym Slawomira Kinastowskiego; [zespol autorski Jozef Dutkiewicz ... et al.] Kitchener, Ont.: Okregowy Komitet Milenium Polski Chrzescijanskiej, Sekcja Wydawnicza, Sekcja Kola Zolnierzy P.S.Z.,1968, Bulk, 1980-1990; 1911-1990 (Box 4, Object 2)
- The following are miniature editions from SPOTKANIA, Paris: - “Rodowody Niepokornych” by Bohdan Cywi_ski - “Doswiadczenie polskie” by Bohdan Cywi_ski - Jozef Grzesiak “Czarny” by A. Kami_ski & A. Wasilewski - “Na nieludzkiej ziemi” by Jozef Czapski - “Zapluty Karzel Reakcji” by Piotr Wo_niak - “Dwa Komitety 1920-1944" by T. Zenczykowski - Libertas, Kwartalnik spoleczno-polityczny 4/85, 1985 (Box 4, Object 3)
- Various publications: - Statut Niezaleznego Zwiazku Zawodowego “Solidarnosc” - “New political thinking and the world trade union movement” by Vsevolod Mozhayev, Moscow, 1990 - “ZweiVaterlander-zwei Patriotismen” by Jan Jozef Lipski, printed in: Magazin Kontinent 22 - “Cultural Development of working people” by Stanislav Kramarenko, Moscow,1989, 1980-1990 (Box 4, Object 4)
- "Wolny Glos Ursusa" (1989), "Mlody Ursus" (1989) (Polish) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Sierpien ‘80 w szczecinskiej Stoczni Remontowej ‘Gryfia,’", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- “Coming Back to the West” by A. Krauze 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- “Ruch Solidarnosci Rodzin”, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- “Odwazny Zwrot” by R. Reiff, Wola., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Samorzad: Informator Grupy Roboczej na rzecz Miedzyregionalnej Inicjatywy wspolpracy samorzadow Pracowniczych", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "BI Biuletyn Informacyjny Zarzadu Fabrycznego NSZZ Solidarnosc w Zakladach Mechanicznych 'Ursus'", no. 1-8,11,13-22., 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Wiadomosci Dnia OBS i BI NSZZ Solidarnosc, Region Mazowsze", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Niezaleznosc: pismo NSZZ Solidarnosc, Mazowsze", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- The Globe and Mail - clippings, pt.1, 1981-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Globe and Mail - clippings, pt.2, 1981-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Toronto Sun - clippings, pt.1, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Toronto Sun - clippings, pt.2, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Clippings from various American and Canadian newspapers and magazine., 1981-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Clippings from communist press in Poland., 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Clippings from leftist press., 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Glos Polski – clippings., 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Toronto Star – clippings., 1981-1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Toronto Star – clippings., 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Echo Tygodnia – clippings., 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Zwiazkowiec – clippings., 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- A Christmas Message for Poland, Guest book, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)